L’Aerophile Collection
Science, Technology, & Business Division, Library of Congress
- Photographs (Box 45-74)
  - Aircraft accidents. (Box 45)
    - Accidents Before WWI. (Envelope 10)
      - Photograph taken after Henri Rougier’s accident (possibly at the Meeting d’Aviation Nice, April, 1910). (Item 22)
      - Photograph of Adolphe Pégoud’s crashed aircraft after his successful parachute jump, August 19, 1913. (Item 23)
      - Photograph of destroyed hangars after a tornado, April, 1910. (Item 24)
      - Six unidentified photographs of airplane accidents. (Item 25)
      - Seven attached photographs of Farman’s aircraft and hangars destroyed after a hurricane (“ouragan”), February, 1914. (Item 26)
      - Three attached photographs of fire extinguishers applied to Deroye’s accident, 1914. (Item 27)
      - Three attached photographs of Graziolli’s accident in Issy Les Moulineaux, March, 1912. (Item 28)
      - Eleven attached photographs and a clipping of Védrine’s accident in Deauville, France. August 18, 1911. (Item 29)
      - Two attached photographs of Maximo Ramo’s aircraft after he crashed in Madrid, January, 1914. Ramos was an aviator in the Spanish Military. (Item 30)
    - Accidents Before WWI #2. (Envelope 11)
      - Four photographs taken after Lieutenant Princeteau’s accident in Issy Les Moulineaux, June, 1911. (Item 1)
      - Two photographs of Le Blon’s accident in St. Sebastian, Spain. April 2, 1910. (Item 2)
      - Photograph of the Italian aviator, B.J Manio’s crash landing on a rooftop in Palmers Green, London. December, 1912. (Item 3)
      - Photograph of M. Hauvette-Michelin’s accident at the Grand Semaine d’Aviation in Heliopolis, Egypt, 1910. (Item 4)
      - Two photographs taken after Laffont’s accident in Issy Les Moulineaux, 1910. (Item 5)
      - Two photographs of Paul Hesne’s accident on a Wright Biplane at Cannes. (Item 6)
      - Two photographs of Claude Grahame-White’s accident. (Item 7)
      - Photograph of “Robinson” (William Leefe?) after a hydroplane accident. (Item 8)
      - Photograph of a biplane accident at the Grand Prix d’Aviation in Issy Les Moulineaux, December 1910. (Item 9)
      - Photograph of a biplane accident in Nice, April 1910. (Item 10)
      - Three photographs of a hydroplane accident in Monaco, (possibly constructed by Henri Fabre), April 1911. (Item 11)
      - Three photographs of hangars destroyed by tornadoes, 1910. (Item 12)
      - Two photographs of Maurice Guffroy’s accident, February 1909. (Item 13)
      - Photograph of British aviator Douglas Graham Gilmour’s funeral procession held in Brooklands, February 1912. Gilmour crashed on a flight from Brooklands to Richmond. (Item 14)
      - Two photographs of hydroplane accidents in Monaco, one from 1913. (Item 15)
      - Seventeen unidentified photographs of airplane accidents, destroyed hangars and burning debris. (Item 16)
      - Three photographs mounted on cardboard of a hydroplane accident in Monaco and views of the aircraft before it crashed, April 1911. (Item 17)
    - Accidents Before WWI #3. (Envelope 12)
      - Two photographs of Blanchard’s Bleriot after an accident. (Item 1)
      - Photograph of Deroye’s accident. (Item 2)
      - Photograph of Gustav Hamel’s accident during the Gordon Bennett Cup, 1911. (Item 3)
      - Three photographs after an accident at the Grand Prix Balloon Race in the Tuileries Gardens. Both M. Blanchet and M. Duval were seriously injured after Blanchet’s balloon collided with the trees in July, 1914. The photographs show policemen rushing to carry the aviators to medical assistance. (Item 4)
      - Photograph of Héléne Dutrieux’s accident in Issy Les Moulineaux, 1910. (Item 5)
      - Two photographs of François Denhaut’s accident while testing his Hydroplane in the Seine River, March 11, 1912. (Item 6)
      - Twenty unidentified photographs of airplane accidents. (Item 7)
      - Sixteen photographs of Hubert Latham’s accidents while attempting to cross the English Channel, 1909. The photographs document the rescue of Latham’s Antoinette IV and its return to Calais. The White Cliffs of Dover can be seen in the distance of at least one photograph, meaning that the photograph is likely from Latham’s second attempt to cross the Channel. July 19 and 27, 1909. (Item 8)
      - Eight photographs of an accident at a military aviation contest at Rheims, October 1911. (Item 9)
      - Four unidentified photographs of an airplane accident. (Item 10)
    - USA. (Envelope 13)
      - Photograph of sailors recovering from the “Akron.” (Item 1)
      - Photograph of James (Jimmie) Mattern’s aircraft “Century of Progress” after landing on the island of Jomfruland, Norway while making a second attempt to circumnavigate the globe in June, 1933. Mattern was the first aviator to make a nonstop flight between the United States and Norway. The photograph depicts two horses pulling Mattern’s plane after a rocky landing in Jomfruland. (Item 2)
      - Photograph of the semi-rigid airship “J-3” after its accident off the coast of New Jersey. (Item 3)
      - Two photographs of Jim and Amy Mollison after their crash-landing in Bridgeport, Connecticut in 1933. The pair had attempted to fly from Pendine Sands, South Wales to New York but ran out of fuel. (Item 4)
      - Photograph of W.A. Hatcher’s aircraft with the caption “Sauve Par Son Parachute” (Saved By His Parachute), 1935. (Item 5)
      - Photograph of the Boeing 299 bomber accident in Dayton, Ohio 1935. (Item 6)
      - Photograph of Wiley Post and the “Winnier Mae” after it was forced to land at Muroc Dry Lake in 1935. Post had attempted to make a stratospheric test flight between Los Angeles and New York. (Item 7)
      - Five unidentified accident photos. (Item 8)
      - Photograph of August C. Haller after parachuting from his plane near Elmira, New York 1933. (Item 9)
      - Two photographs of members from the Commission of Inquiry of the U.S Navy examining the remains of the airship “Akron” in Lakehurst, New Jersey. (Item 10)
      - Photograph of an airplane rented by the Princess de Polignac and her brother, Jacques Du Puy in Miami. The plane crashed into the Biscayne Bay and the pair was rescued by a fisherman, 1934. (Item 11)
      - Two photographs of Francesco de Pinedo’s aircraft before and after takeoff. One photograph shows Pinedo’s plane engulfed in flames. Pinedo had intended to fly from New York City to Baghdad, 1933. (Item 12)
    - England, R.101. (Envelope 14)
      - Four photographs taken after the accident of the R.101. The dirigible was on its maiden voyage to India when it crashed near Beauvais, October, 1930. (Item 1)
    - Balloon Accidents. (Envelope 15)
      - Three unidentified photographs of balloon accidents including a 1911 picture of a Farman biplane accident. (Item 1)
      - Two attached photographs of Bradsky’s dirigible accident in Paris, October, 1902. (Item 2)
      - Four attached photographs of Clement Bayard’s dirigible accident in the Seine River. (Item 3)
      - Two attached photographs of a Astra-Torres dirigible accident. (Item 4)
    - “Emeraude”, 1934. (Envelope 16)
      - Last picture of M. Pasquier, Governor General of Indochina taken before he boarded the “Emeraude,” 1934. (Item 1)
      - Five photographs of the debris from the “Emeraude” after it crashed near Corbigny and Nevers, France. (Item 2)
    - French Accidents: Trains. (Envelope 17)
      - Three photographs taken after an accident of a train traveling from Paris to Le Croisic. (Item 1)
    - French Dirigibles Accidents. (Envelope 18)
      - Photograph of balloon descending in flames after a successful test of airplane maneuvers, May, 1933. (Item 1)
      - Two photographs taken after the dirigible “E-9” accident. (Item 2)
  - Commercial airlines (various countries, inc. Britain, France, Germany, the Netherlands, U.S.). (Box 46)
    - Airlines (Various Countries). (Envelope 1)
    - Air Routes (Belgium). (Envelope 2)
    - Air Routes (England). (Envelope 3)
    - Air Routes (France). (Envelope 4)
    - Air Routes (Germany). (Envelope 5)
    - Air Routes (Italy). (Envelope 6)
    - Air Routes (Netherlands, Holland). (Envelope 7)
    - Air Routes (Romania). (Envelope 8)
    - Air Routes (Russia). (Envelope 9)
    - Air Routes (Switzerland). (Envelope 10)
    - Airlines (USA). (Envelope 11)
  - Air Mail Photographs. (Box 47)
    - Airmail. (Envelope 1)
      - Two attached photographs of an early airmail plane and a German airmail cover. (Item 1)
      - Larger photograph of the German airmail cover (see ITEM 1). (Item 2)
      - Two photographs of a German airmail plane. (Item 3)
    - France. (Envelope 2)
      - Two photographs of French postage stamps that depict balloons and airplanes, 1936. (Item 1)
      - Photograph of George Mandel, Minister of Posts, Telegraphs, and Telephones, with the French Air Minister; July, 1935. (Item 2)
      - Photograph of an airplane loading airmail from a French postal truck. (Item 3)
      - Three views of an early airmail delivery leaving from Villacoublay. (Item 4)
      - Three photographs of airmail being loaded onto an Air France airplane. (Item 5)
    - USA. (Envelope 3)
      - Photograph of “Une nouvelle invention,” an invention that allowed airplanes to receive mail without landing or reducing speed. (Item 1)
      - Photograph demonstrating a method of transporting valuables by airmail. (Item 2)
      - Photograph of a postal employee sorting outgoing airmail, 1934. (Item 3)
      - Two photographs of loading and unloading airmail. (Item 4)
    - England. (Envelope 4)
      - Photograph of the new airmail transport designed by the Air Ministry and completed in Norwich. (Item 1)
    - Germany. (Envelope 5)
      - Photograph of Walter Angermund’s airmail invention. Angermund was the Air Communications Director of Munich. (Item 1)
      - Photograph of a German airmail plane bound for South America; April, 1935. (Item 2)
  - Air Maneuvers, military, various countries, prior to WWII. (Box 48)
    - England. (Envelope 1)
    - Germany. (Envelope 2)
    - Italy. (Envelope 3)
    - Japan. (Envelope 4)
    - USA. (Envelope 5)
    - France. (Envelope 6)
    - Before the War. (Envelope 7)
  - Personalities (post-WWI). (Box 49)
    - Named Air Personalities (France). (Envelope 1)
    - Unknown French Personalities. (Envelope 2)
    - Obituary: George Besancon (Envelope 3)
    - Photos: Max Holste, 1942. (Envelope 4)
    - Photos: Aviator, M. Farman. (Envelope 5)
    - Capitaine Georges Guynemer. (Envelope 6)
    - Photos: Aviator, Leopold-Roger. (Envelope 7)
    - Graham White. (Envelope 8)
    - Piccard Brothers. (Envelope 9)
    - Photos: U.S Aviators: Langley. (Envelope 10)
    - U.S Air Personalities. (Envelope 11)
    - Photos: German Aviators. (Envelope 12)
    - Listings of Decorated Aviators. (Envelope 13)
    - U.S Air Personalities. (Envelope 14)
    - Photos: Student Pilots. (Envelope 15)
    - Photos: Pilots. (Envelope 16)
    - Unknown American Aviators. (Envelope 17)
    - Named Air Personalities (USA). (Envelope 18)
    - Marriages of Various Aviators. (Envelope 19)
    - Albert Francis Zahm. (Envelope 20)
    - Index: Photos of Personalities. (Envelope 21)
  - Air shows/Exhibits. 1909-1930. (Box 50)
    - Aviation Shows, 1909. (Envelope 1)
    - Aviation Shows, 1910. (Envelope 2)
    - Aviation Shows, 1911-1913. (Envelope 3)
    - Aviation Shows, 1921-1922. (Envelope 4)
    - Aeronautics Show, 1924. (Envelope 5)
    - Aeronautics Show, 1926. (Envelope 6)
    - Aeronautics Show 1928. (Envelope 7)
    - Aeronautics Show 1930. (Envelope 8)
  - Air Shows/Exhibits. 1931-1948. (Box 51)
    - Photos: Aeronautics Show 1932. (Envelope 1)
    - Photos: Aeronautics Show 1934. (Envelope 2)
    - Photos: Aeronautics Show 1936. (Envelope 3)
    - Photos: Aeronautics Show, 1938. (Envelope 4)
    - Photos: Aeronautics Show Yugoslavia, 1938. (Envelope 5)
    - Photos: Air Show France 1940 (“Salon de la France”). (Envelope 6)
    - Photos: Air Show, 1946. (Envelope 7)
    - Photos: Air Show “Hare & Tortoise” England, 1948. (Envelope 8)
    - Photos: Beaux Arts Air Show. (Envelope 9)
    - Photos: Milan Air Show, 1946. (Envelope 10)
    - Photos: Air Shows France. (Envelope 11)
    - Photos: Aeronautics Air Shows. (Envelope 12)
    - Photos: 1937 Exhibit. (Envelope 13)
    - Aeronautic Shows and Exhibits. (Envelope 14)
    - Aeronautic Shows and Exhibits #2. (Envelope 15)
  - Receptions, festivals, banquets prior to WWII: A-C. (Box 52)
    - Aero Club-Grand Prix. (Envelope 1)
    - Aero Club Receptions. (Envelope 2)
    - Air Festivals (Belgium). (Envelope 3)
    - Air Festivals (France). (Envelope 4)
    - Balls, Festivals, Parties & Banquets. (Envelope 5)
    - Aircraft Baptisms (Envelope 6)
    - Ceremonies Before WWI. (Envelope 7)
  - Receptions, festivals, banquets prior to WWII: D-Z. (Box 53)
    - ”Concours Jeunes Tigres”, 1943. (Envelope 1)
    - Concours National, 1963. (Envelope 2)
    - Commerations. (Envelope 3)
    - Miscellaneous Commemorations. (Envelope 4)
    - Costes, Brix & Bellonte Receptions. (Envelope 5)
    - Coupes (“Remises de Coupes”). (Envelope 6)
    - Decoration Ceremonies. (Envelope 7)
    - Inauguration du L’er Salon de l’Aeronautique. (Envelope 8)
    - Inaugurations. (Envelope 9)
    - Miscellaneous Receptions. (Envelope 10)
    - Yankee Clipper Reception of American Journalists. (Envelope 11)
  - Coupes (spherical balloons): Gordon Bennett (1906-1913), Schneider, Deutsch. (Box 54)
    - Coupe Gordon Bennett (Balloon Spheriques). (Envelope 1)
      - Three photographs of “petit” airplanes at the Coupe Gordon Bennett, 1920. (Item 1)
      - Photograph of an aviator in a “cross country monoplane” at the 1913 Coupe Gordon Bennett in Rheims. (Item 2)
      - Two photographs from the 1932 Coupe Gordon Bennett in Basel, Switzerland. (Item 3)
      - Photograph from the 1934 Coupe Gordon Bennett in Warsaw, Poland. (Item 4)
      - Five photographs from various Coupe Gordon Bennetts held between 1920-1936. (Item 5)
    - Coupe Gordon Bennett, 1906. (Envelope 2)
      - Four photographs from the first Coupe Gordon Bennett, held in the Jardin des Tuileries, Paris, 1906. (Item 1)
    - Coupe Gordon Bennett, 1908. (Envelope 3)
      - Thirteen photographs from the third Coupe Gordon Bennett, held in Berlin. The pictures include views of the “Isle de France” and scenes of balloons inflating and departing. (Item 1)
    - Coupe Gordon Bennett, 1909. (Envelope 4)
      - Nine photographs of the 1909 Coupe Gordon Bennett held in Zurich, Switzerland. (Item 1)
      - Three photographs of the aviators involved in the 1909 Coupe Gordon Bennett, including Edgar W. Mix, Theodor Schaeck, and Emil Messner. (Item 2)
    - Coupe Gordon Bennett, 1911-1912. (Envelope 5)
      - Five photographs and a clipping from the 1911 and 1912 Coupe Gordon Bennett. (Item 1)
    - Coupe Gordon Bennett, 1913. (Envelope 6)
      - Twenty two photographs from the 1913 Coupe Gordon Bennett held in the Jardin de Tuileries, Paris. The pictures feature the Italian balloon “Roma,” the Belgian “Belgica II,” and the Austrian “Astarte.” (Item 1)
    - Coupe Schneider. (Envelope 7)
      - Eleven photographs of hydroplanes from the Coupe Schneider, including two group photos, 1927 and 1931. (Item 1)
    - “Coupe Deutsch de la Meurthe.” (Envelope 8)
      - Photograph of the jury for the contest. (Item 1)
      - Thirty four photographs of aviators and airplanes at the Coupe Deutsche de la Meurthe, 1921, 1933-1936. The photographs include pictures of Détré, Caudron and the French War Minister. (Item 2)
      - Sixteen attached photographs of aviators and airplanes at the Coupe Deutsche de la Meurthe, 1935. (Item 3)
  - Aeronautical equipment. (Box 55)
    - Equipment Parts (France). (Envelope 1)
    - Photos: Airplane items and Parts. (Envelope 2)
    - Equipment for Taking Aerial Photos. (Envelope 3)
    - Aerodynamic Equipment (USA). (Envelope 4)
    - Air Equipment (Envelope 5)
    - Air Equipment (Publications and Photographs). (Envelope 6)
    - Equipment (“Amortisseur de Goureme”). (Envelope 7)
    - Autogenus Welding. (Envelope 8)
    - Flight Control Equipment (England). (Envelope 9)
    - Flight Control Equipment (France). (Envelope 10)
    - Flight Control Equipment (Holland). (Envelope 11)
    - Flight Control Equipment (Germany). (Envelope 12)
    - Flight Control Equipment (Italy). (Envelope 13)
    - Flight Control Equipment (Poland). (Envelope 14)
    - Flight Control Equipment (USA). (Envelope 15)
    - Equipment (Greece). (Envelope 16)
    - Instruments de Pilotage. (Envelope 17)
    - Aircrafts: Interior Instrument Panels. (Envelope 18)
    - Life Saving Equipment (Belgium). (Envelope 19)
    - Life Saving Equipment (Germany). (Envelope 20)
    - Life Saving Equipment (USA). (Envelope 21)
    - On Board Equipment (England). (Envelope 22)
    - Arial Cameras. (Envelope 23)
    - Compasses. (Envelope 24)
    - Control Equipment. (Envelope 25)
    - Defroster. (Envelope 26)
    - Photos & Diagrams of Equipment Parts. (Envelope 27)
    - Factory Equipment. (Envelope 28)
    - Pilot Equipment. (Envelope 29)
    - Radio Equipment (Germany) (Envelope 30)
    - Radio Equipment. (Envelope 31)
    - Radio Direction Finding Equipment (France). (Envelope 32)
    - Equipment- Slide Rule. (Envelope 33)
    - Equipment Security (Italy). (Envelope 34)
    - Equipment Security Control (USA). (Envelope 35)
    - Shock Cord (France). (Envelope 36)
    - Stabilizer. (Envelope 37)
    - Stabilizer (USA). (Envelope 38)
    - On Board Instruments. (Envelope 39)
  - Photographs of Meetings, Conferences. (Box 56)
    - Miscellaneous Coupes & Meetings. (Envelope 1)
    - Miscellaneous Meetings #1. (Envelope 2)
    - Meeting Aerien de Nice, 1947. (Envelope 3)
    - Buc Meeting, 1920. (Envelope 4)
    - Coupes et Meetings de Vincennes. (Envelope 5)
    - “Cousseus le Noble” Meeting, 1946. (Envelope 6)
    - Mans International Meeting. (Envelope 7)
    - Saint Germain Meeting. (Envelope 8)
    - Saint Raphael Meeting. (Envelope 9)
    - Miscellaneous Meetings #2. (Envelope 10)
  - Photos: Aerobatics, aerodromes, airports. (Box 57)
    - Aerobatics (England). (Envelope 1)
    - Aerobatics (France). (Envelope 2)
    - Aerobatics (Germany). (Envelope 3)
    - Aerobatics (Italy). (Envelope 4)
    - Aerobatics (USA). (Envelope 5)
    - “Aero Cible Michelin” (France). (Envelope 6)
    - Aero-Club. (Envelope 7)
    - “Aerodromes” (Canada). (Envelope 8)
    - “Aerodromes” (England). (Envelope 9)
    - “Aerodromes” (France). (Envelope 10)
    - “Aerodromes” (Germany). (Envelope 11)
    - “Aerodromes” (Japan). (Envelope 12)
    - “Aerodromes” (Sweden). (Envelope 13)
    - “Aerodromes” photographs and diagram (USA). (Envelope 14)
    - “Materiel Aerodrome.” (Envelope 15)
    - L’Aerodrome (Paris). (Envelope 16)
    - Air Ministry. (Envelope 17)
    - Air Ministry (Italy). (Envelope 18)
    - Air Signals (Japan). (Envelope 19)
    - Airports (France). (Envelope 20)
    - Airports #1. (Envelope 21)
    - Airports #2. (Envelope 22)
    - Various Airports and Air Stations. (Envelope 23)
    - Aircraft Carrier Ships (“Navires Porte Avions”). (Envelope 24)
    - Armament (Czechoslovakia). (Envelope 25)
    - Armament (England). (Envelope 26)
    - Armament (France). (Envelope 27)
    - Armament (Italy). (Envelope 28)
    - Armament (Sweden & Norway). (Envelope 29)
    - Armament (Switzerland). (Envelope 30)
    - Armament/Weaponry (USA). (Envelope 31)
    - “Artificial Clouds.” (Envelope 32)
    - “Attestatations.” (Envelope 33)
    - Automatic Pilot. (Envelope 34)
  - Automobiles, including electric, Avion Laboratoire, challenges de tourisme, cinema, circuits. (Box 58)
    - Automobiles (International). (Envelope 1)
      - Photograph of Captain Malcolm Campbell’s “Bluebird,” which set a new speed record in 1931 at Daytona Beach at 231 mph. (Item 1)
      - Photograph of an airplane piloted by Assolant and Lefevre in an attempt to fly from New York to Europe, April, 1929. (Item 2)
      - Photograph of “un modele reduit d'un nouveau systeme de transport appele le ‘Railplane’" (a scale model of a new transport system called the ‘Railplane’). The design was submitted by Mr. Charles Boot, the London Minister of Public Health, 1935. (Item 3)
      - Photograph of the 39th Bordeaux-Paris, the oldest cycling race. (Item 4)
    - Electric-Powered Cars (France), 1940. (Envelope 2)
    - Electric-Powered Cars 1940. (Envelope 3)
    - “Avion Laboratuire.” (Envelope 4)
    - “Challenges de Tourisme.” (Envelope 5)
    - “Chronometreage Enregistrement Observation” (Timing Registration Remarks). (Envelope 6)
    - Cinema/Movies. (Envelope 7)
    - Circuit de l’Est. (Envelope 8)
    - “Circuit d’Anjou”, 1912. (Envelope 9)
    - “Circuit European.” (Envelope 10)
    - Congress. (Envelope 11)
    - Course Paris and Rome. (Envelope 12)
  - Courses (routes), destroyed aircraft, eclipse 1905, factories, floating islands, ground lighting, hangars, human-powered flight, inventions, Laboratoire Eiffel, memorial services, monuments. (Box 59)
    - Course Paris-Madrid. (Envelope 1)
    - “Distinctions Honorifiques.” (Envelope 2)
    - Destroyed Aircraft. (Envelope 3)
    - Eclipse, 1905. (Envelope 4)
    - Factories. (Envelope 5)
    - Floating Islands. (Envelope 6)
    - ”Grand Semaine de Reims.” (Envelope 7)
    - Ground Lighting and Signals. (Envelope 8)
    - Ground Lighting (USA). (Envelope 9)
    - Hangars (France). (Envelope 10)
    - Hangars (USA). (Envelope 11)
    - Human Flight. (Envelope 12)
    - Human Flight. (Envelope 13)
    - Infrastructure (USA). (Envelope 14)
    - Institut Aerotechnique. (Envelope 15)
    - Inventions (France). (Envelope 16)
    - Inventions (England). (Envelope 17)
    - Inventions (Germany). (Envelope 18)
    - Laboratoire Eiffel. (Envelope 19)
    - Memorial Services. (Envelope 20)
    - Memorial Service for Victims of “L’Emeraude.” (Envelope 21)
    - Mercantile Marine (USA). (Envelope 22)
    - Meteorology (England). (Envelope 23)
    - Monuments, Notices & Insignias. (Envelope 24)
  - Monuments, insignia, museums, observatories, medical experiments, polar flights, refueling in air, salons. (Box 60)
    - Monuments, Insignias, Art Objects. (Envelope 1)
    - Museums. (Envelope 2)
    - Observatories (Photos and one Manuscript). (Envelope 3)
    - Physiology Medical Experiments. (Envelope 4)
    - Salon d’Aviation (France). (Envelope 5)
    - Official Visits. (Envelope 6)
    - Plants (USA). (Envelope 7)
    - Polar Bears. (Envelope 8)
    - Polar Flights. (Envelope 9)
    - Rallies. (Envelope 10)
    - Aerial Refueling (USA). (Envelope 11)
    - Reservoirs (France). (Envelope 12)
    - Reviewing of the Troops. (Envelope 13)
    - Publication: Salon Internationale (Yugoslavia). (Envelope 14)
    - Publication: Second Salon de Milan. (Envelope 15)
  - Schools for aviators, sports, Wellman Polar Expedition, wind tunnels, wings (experimental designs). (Box 61)
    - Schools (France). (Envelope 1)
    - Sports. (Envelope 2)
    - Tour of England. (Envelope 3)
    - Aviation in the Theater. (Envelope 4)
    - Timing & Recording. (Envelope 5)
    - Transatlantic Boats. (Envelope 6)
    - Traveling Across the Atlantic. (Envelope 7)
    - Trucks, “Roulottes” (Mobile Repair Stations) and Hangars. (Envelope 8)
    - T.S.F Before WWI. (Envelope 9)
    - T.S.F England. (Envelope 10)
    - La Valette. (Envelope 11)
    - Water Tank, 1931. (Envelope 12)
    - Electric Welding (Languepin). (Envelope 13)
    - Experimental Designs for Wings. (Envelope 14)
    - Wind Tunnel. (Envelope 15)
    - Welleman Polar Expedition. (Envelope 16)
    - Wuillemin Squadron. (Envelope 17)
  - Misc. Photos by country. (Box 62)
    - Miscellaneous Photos: France. (Envelope 1)
    - Miscellaneous Photos: Miscellaneous Countries. (Envelope 2)
    - Miscellaneous Photos: England. (Envelope 3)